First of all, thank you so much for being here with us. I want to ask you a few questions.
首先，非常感谢您 与我们在一起。 我想问你几个问题。
First of all, tell me a little bit about the relationship you have with yourself?
首先，请告诉我一些关于 您与自己的关系？
With myself before the accident?
和事故发生前的自己？
Both.
两个都。
Both. Who was on social media? Who's using Facebook? Everyone.
两个都。 谁在社交媒体上？ 谁在使用 Facebook？ 每个人。
Have you ever put your relationship status complicated? My relationship with myself,
你有没有把你的关系状态 复杂化？
before I was here was so complicated. It was all about people. It was never about me.
在我来到这里之前，我与自己的关系是如此复杂。 一切都是关于人的。 从来都不是关于我的。
There was no me anywhere. You see people's pleaser. The person who just wants to make
任何地方都没有我。 你看到了人们的 喜悦。 一个只想让
everyone happy knowing that it's not worth it. You just keep doing it. Keep doing it. And yes,
每个人都开心的人，知道这不值得。 你只要继续做就行了。 继续做。 是的，
your relationship eventually with yourself becomes complicated.
你与自己的关系最终 会变得复杂。
And then now, I don't know where there are people around me or not, but I me now. I'm more me now.
然后现在，我不知道我周围有没有人 ，但我现在是我。 我现在更像我了。
That's so nice. What advice would you give to your younger self?
那太好了。 你会给年轻的自己什么建议？
To my younger self? Interesting question! Well, I'll just make her sit next to me
对年轻的自己？ 有趣的问题！ 好吧，我会让她坐在我旁边
and very nicely, I'll tell her. Don't invest yourself in the wrong people. Because when you
，非常好，我会告诉她的。 不要把 自己投资在错误的人身上。 因为当你
invest yourself in the wrong people, they break you into pieces, they torn you apart
把自己投资在错误的人身上时，他们会把 你打成碎片，把你撕成碎片
in such a way that it takes years and years to get back together.
，以至于你需要很多 年才能重新团结起来。
And also, I will tell her that while you are busy making amazing plans in your life,
而且，我会告诉她，当 你忙着为你的生活制定惊人的计划时，
my dear, prepare yourself for worse. Because life is so unpredictable. Just be prepared.
亲爱的，请为更糟的情况做好准备。 因为 生活是如此不可预测。 只要做好准备。
One of my philosophies in life is, is that there are three steps in order to repair your life.
我的人生哲学之一是， 为了修复你的生活，有三个步骤。
First of all, is to change your personal story, then your daily rituals, and then
首先，是改变你的个人 故事，然后是你的日常仪式，然后
the people, you surround yourself. I believe so much in these. So tell me,
是你周围的人。 我 非常相信这些。 所以告诉我，
Time is a beautiful teacher. It filters out the extras from your life, including people.
时间是一位美丽的老师。 它会过滤 掉你生活中的额外内容，包括人。
Being in the wheelchair in 12 years, I've had three categories of people.
坐轮椅 12 年， 我有过三类人。
Number one category is of the people who see you in the misery in pain and the backoff,
第一类是那些 在痛苦和退缩中看到你的人，
they're like we are gone. We can't handle it. I respect them for their honesty.
他们就像我们走了一样。 我们无法处理 它。 我尊重他们的诚实。
Then there is another category of the people who are not there with you, but they just want
还有一类 人不在你身边，但他们只是
to cling on with you all the time. They're so weak, that they try to stay in your shadow.
想一直和你在一起。 他们是如此的 虚弱，以至于他们试图留在你的影子里。
Liberate yourself from those people, because they are toxic for you.
把自己从那些人身上解放出来， 因为他们对你有毒。
Don't let them cling on to you because they're not there to help you,
不要让他们粘着你， 因为他们不是来帮助你，
liberate them, liberate yourself, and then there is the third category. These beautiful people who
解放他们，解放你自己，然后 是第三类。 这些美丽的人
are so selfless, that when they see you in pain, they stand next to you. They've got your back.
是如此无私，以至于当他们看到你痛苦时， 他们会站在你身边。 他们支持你。
They don't share the limelight. They're just there for you.
他们不分享风头。 他们只是为你而存在。
These are your people value them. So yes, there are three categories of people try
这些是你的人所重视的。 所以是的， 有三类人
to surround yourself with those who are real, and you will feel real.
试图让自己与真实的人 在一起，你会感觉真实。
What about jealousy?
嫉妒呢？
What about? About jealousy.
关于什么？
Jealousy? I pity them. I pity those who see their failure in your success. You know, these critics,
妒忌？ 我可怜他们。 我同情那些 在你的成功中看到自己失败的人。 你知道，这些批评家，
they were once dreamers. They just wanted to achieve something that today you have, but they
他们曾经是梦想家。 他们只是想 实现你今天所拥有的东西，但
gave up and they started becoming jealous of you. Pray for them because they're in a lot of pain.
他们放弃了，开始嫉妒你。 为他们祈祷，因为他们很痛苦。
One of the things that I see usually when I do therapy, a lot of women, they prefer
我在进行治疗时通常会看到的一件事是 ，很多女性更
to stay in a miserable relationship instead of get out. The fear of being alone is greater.
愿意保持悲惨的关系而不是 离开。 孤独的恐惧更大。
So would you give some advice to these women?
那么，您会给这些女性一些建议吗？
We all tend to invest ourselves in relationships. And as I said,
我们都倾向于将自己投资 于人际关系。 正如我所说，
if you are doing something right, but the wrong person, nothing good will turn out,
如果你做对了某事，但选 错了人，结果就不会是好的，
and deep inside, we were quite intuitive. We know that it's not going anywhere.
而且在内心深处，我们非常直觉。 我们知道它不会去任何地方。
It's okay to be on your own. You are stronger than you think. Don't worry about that,
自己一个人也没关系。 你 比你想像的要坚强。 不用担心
and wait for the right person. Let the right person come to you. There's no rush. Are you in
，等待合适的人。 让合适的 人来找你。 不用着急。 你
a good relationship with yourself? Do you love your own company? If you're miserable alone,
和自己的关系好吗？ 你爱 你自己的公司吗？ 如果你一个人难受，
I'm sorry, your partner will be miserable with you. So we need to understand
对不起，你的伴侣会 和你一起难受。 所以我们需要明白
that we need to love our own company, only then people will love to enjoy our company too.
，我们需要爱我们自己的公司，只有 这样人们才会喜欢享受我们的公司。
And don't rush. Wait for the right person. Because if it's meant to be, it will be.
不要着急。 等待对的人。 因为如果它是注定的，它会的。
One of the things I usually say is that your relationships reflect your self relationships. So
我经常说的一件事是，你的 人际关系反映了你的自我关系。
the most important thing is to look within to fix the most important relationship that is
所以最重要的事情是向内看， 修复最重要的关系，即
the relationship you have with yourself. Muniba, I want to ask you, how do you want to be remembered?
你与自己的关系。 穆尼巴，我 想问你，你想怎样被人记住？
Such a beautiful question.
这么漂亮的问题。
I want to be remembered as an empath. Somebody who just didn't say that I feel your pain,
我想被人们铭记为移情者。 只是没有说我感受到你的痛苦的人，
but I want people to see that when I say this I mean it. And as far as my life story is concerned,
但我希望人们看到，当我说这句话时，我 是认真的。 就我的人生故事而言，
I don't know how my story will end. Maybe it will never end,
我不知道我的故事会如何 结束。 也许它永远不会结束
but yes, nowhere in my text, the world will ever read I gave up.
，但是是的，在我的文字中， 世界永远不会读我放弃。
Apart from art, What kept you going in life?
除了艺术，是什么让你在生活中继续前进？
I think all sorts of art kept me going. I love music. I used to sing. I still sing
我想各种各样的艺术让我继续前进。 我 爱音乐。 我曾经唱歌。 我仍然
lullabies for my son, and just like painting art music is so therapeutic. So I love music.
为我的儿子唱摇篮曲，就像绘画 艺术音乐一样具有治疗作用。 所以我喜欢音乐。
I don't know if the crowd would love that. If it's okay with you, would you mind sing
不知道大众会不会喜欢。 如果你没关系，你介意
something for us? Just to listen to your voice.
为我们唱首歌吗？ 只为聆听你的声音。
Have you watched Tangled? Tangled Rapunzel her journey how she comes out of confinement for the
你看过《纠结》吗？ 纠结于长发公主的 旅程，她是如何第一次摆脱束缚的
first time. She goes out and sees the world awaits her. You know what that song "I see the light"
。 她走出去，看到世界在等着 她。 你知道那首歌“I see the light”是什么，
it reminds me of the times when I was bedridden,
它让我想起了我卧床不起的时候
and I used to hear the kids playing outside. I couldn't see it. I used to hear thunderclap
，我曾经听到孩子们在外面玩耍。 我看不见。 我曾经听到雷声，
I couldn't see the storms. I used to hear the rain falling on the ground. I couldn't see it,
我看不到暴风雨。 我曾经听到 雨落在地上。 我看不到它
and I missed it. But when I sat in the wheelchair I stepped out went close to nature
，我错过了它。 但是当我坐在 轮椅上时，我走出来亲近大自然，
everything's changed. So this beautiful song I see the light. Probably something I'd like to sing.
一切都变了。 所以这首美妙的歌曲让我看到 了曙光。 大概是我想唱的东西。
"All those days watching from the windows
“那些日子在窗外看着
All those years outside looking in
所有那些年在外面看着
All that time never even knowing
所有那些时间甚至不知道
Just how blind I've been
我有多盲目
Now I'm here blinking in the starlight
现在我在这里在星光中闪烁
Now I'm here suddenly I see
现在我在这里突然我看到
Standing here it's oh so clear
站在这里它是如此清晰
I'm where I'm meant to be
我到了我该去的
And at last, I see the light
地方最后，我看到了
And it's like the fog has lifted
光，就像雾已经
...the sky is new
……天空是新的
And it's warm and real and bright...
，它温暖、真实、明亮……
And the world has somehow shifted
世界不知何故突然发生了变化
All at once, everything looks different.
，一切看起来都不同了。
Now that I see you.”
现在我看到了你。
God bless you!
上帝保佑你！
Thank you so much. Antonio...
非常感谢你。 安东尼奥......
Here comes the chief guest. He's so adorable! Oh my god!
首席客人来了。 他太可爱了！哦，我的上帝！
Oh, God bless you. Thank you so much.
哦，上帝保佑你。 非常
Thank you.
感谢。非常感谢。谢谢。